Thank you, Professor Guqi, for that introduction.
感谢刚刚古奇老师的介绍
Uh...
呃
First, let me give you a detailed introduction.
首先我来给大家详细介绍一下
So, I'll be talking about some of our team's recent research on visual memory.
我们团队最近在关于视觉记忆方面的一些研究
And as the host just mentioned,
也像刚刚主持人提到了
So, this work of ours on visual memory...
我们这个视觉记忆的工作
Our main focus is on how to use layout-aware visual memory,
主要聚焦于如何通过版面感知的视觉记忆
to enhance effective long-range reasoning.
来增强一些有效的长城推理呃
So, our work itself is focused on
那我们的这个工作本身是聚焦于
how to transform the form of memory
怎么把记忆的形态
from text-based memory to visual memory.
从文本记忆转化为一个视觉记忆
to achieve more efficient long-context compression and, uh...
来实现更有效的长相温压缩和呃
and under higher compression rates,
在更高压缩率的情况下
and push it to handle even longer reasoning sequences.
把把他推到更长的一个推理的长度
So, for this work of ours, uh...
那我们这个工作的像呃
The project homepage and the model weights are all, uh, publicly available.
主页和代码权重都是额放出的
And you can access all of that down below, yeah.
然后在底下都可以访问到对嗯
So first, let me give you a brief introduction.
首先我想来给大家介绍一下
So, about the background of our research...
就是关于我们研究的背景
So, it's about the memory of an agent, uh...
就是智能体的记忆呃
As we all know,
我们都知道
Agents can actually be faced with some very long-term tasks.
智能体居然会面临一些非常长城的任务
For example, uh, some of the, uh, things we all commonly use nowadays...
比如现在我们大家常用的呃一些呃
or AI agents that write code.
写代码的智能题
This includes projects our own team is working on, like LongCat.
包括我们团队本身在做的像long cat这样的
in scenarios involving very long-horizon tasks.
面临一些非常long horizon task的一些场景
So, maintaining an effective memory...
那么维护一个有效的记忆
to enable it to remember for a very long time,
能让他记住很长的
and recall a vast amount of information.
记住很多的信息
to enable it to engage in very long-term interactions.
才能让它进行一个非常长程的交互
So, if we look back at some of the past work on agent memory...
那回顾过去的一些智能体记忆的工作呢
we can see that, uh, past work can be divided into two main categories.
我们会发现呃过去的工作可以被分为两个类别
One category uses, uh, the raw history as its memory.
一类是使用呃原始的历史作为记忆
or what we call raw history memory.
也就是我们称之为绕history memory
Now, this type of memory...
这一类记忆呢
will take some historical interactions and put them into a very large, uh...
会把一些历史的交互给放到一个很大的呃
into a corpus.
corpus里面
and then through active retrieval,
然后通过主动的检索
for instance, using top-k retrieval to find past memories.
比如top kretrieval来去查找历史的记忆
to represent the memory.
来做一个memory的体现
So, what about the other form of memory?
那另一种记忆形式呢
This is done by, uh, having the agents actively summarize the information themselves.
就是通过呃让一些智能体主动去总结
summarizing past interactions into, uh, a textual summary.
把历史的交互总结成文本形式的呃summary
or what we call, Texture Summary Memory.
也就是我们称之为texture summary memory
So, in this kind of format,
在这样的一些形式下
The agent summarizes its own memories.
智能体通过自己去总结记忆
to write some text summaries.
去撰写一些text summary
can take a very long history of interactions,
可以把一个篇幅很长的历史交互
into a relatively shorter piece of text.
总结成一个篇幅相对较短
a more condensed form of text-based memory.
较为浓缩的一个文本记忆形式
So, here we're using, uh, 1K tokens.
我们这里用呃这个1K token
to represent the length of the condensed memory.
来代表浓缩之后的一个记忆的长度
And that's when we ran into a problem.
那我们就发现了一个问题
So, uh, in the roll history memory...
就是说呃在roll history memory里面
We retain the original, uncompressed information.
我们保留原始的未经压缩的信息
in the textural memory, the textual summary memory...
在texture memory texal summary memory里面
we store the information that's been compressed into text.
我们保留用文本压缩的信息
Uh, however, this presents us with a problem.
呃然而我们会面临一个问题
So, uh, with this kind of information compression method,
就是说呃在这样的信息压缩手段下
the truly critical information
我们真正关键的信息
might only make up a small fraction of our total memory.
很有可能只占了我们完整的记忆总量的
a relatively small proportion of it.
其中比较小的比例
For example, uh, under text-based memory,
比如说在呃文本记忆下面
And that's because with text, no matter what kind of text it is,
那因为文本不管是什么样的文本
it's all represented by the same type of token.
它都是以相同的token来表示的
So, uh, whether it's key information,
所以说呃不管是关键的信息
or some supporting facts,
还是说一些supporting fact
or some details,
一些details
they are all represented by tokens of the same density.
他们都是用同样密度的token来表示
So, what we want to store is, uh...
也就是说我们想要储存呃
For instance, key information that takes up 100 tokens,
比如100个token的关键信息
we might need to supplement it with, say, around 900 tokens of other information.
我们可能需要补充900个token这个量级的一些
supporting facts,
Supporting facts
and some details.
一些details
some supplementary information, uh...
一些辅助性的信息呃
So, to tackle this problem...
为了解决这个问题呢
We tried to change the form of memory from a text-based summary
我们尝试把记忆的形式从文本形式的记忆总结
to visual summaries.
拓展到视觉形式的记忆总结
Specifically, we allow the agent to, uh...
具体来说我们允许智能体来呃
to compose its memory within the layout of an image.
在图像的布局下去撰写他的记忆
In other words, we give the agent a canvas.
也就是说我们会给智能体一张画布
Here, it's in the form of, uh, a coding a h.
这里是以呃coding a h的形式
We have it write its own memory in the form of, uh...
我们让它自己以副文本形式撰写一个呃
a visual memory layout.
视觉的记忆版面
within this memory layout,
在记忆版面下
The agent can, uh...
智能体可以以呃
and adjust the density of different information using various visual layouts.
不同的视觉的布局来调整不同信息的密度
This allows it to manage the entire layout,
从而实现对于整个版面的
In other words, it's about the effective allocation of the overall memory budget.
也就是整体的memory budget记预算的一个有效分配
So, in a situation like this, uh...
那在这样的一个情况下呃
So, in the scenario we just mentioned,
像我们刚刚提到的情形
let's say, you want to store something like, uh, around 100 tokens.
想要储存大概100个token左右的一个呃
key information
关键信息
The agent can take some of the less important information,
它可以智能体可以把一些不重要的信息
some supporting facts
一些supporting facts
in a less prominent form,
用相对不那么显著的形式
and place them in, uh, more supplementary sections of the layout.
放在一些呃比较补充性的版面当中
And this is all achieved within the overall layout.
从而实现在整体的布局上面
For more critical information, a lower compression rate is used,
对于更关键的信息使用更低的压缩率
And for the more subtle parts,
然后一些更低调的
while applying a higher compression rate to more detailed, less critical information.
更细节的不关键的信息使用更高的压缩率
And, uh, by using visual compression,
同时呢呃使用视觉压缩的话
We can adjust the overall, that is, the global layout of the entire G-canvas.
我们调整整体的就是整个G版面的一个全局
compression ratio.
压缩比例
This also allows for more flexible adjustments.
也可以更灵活的去调整
For example, we can directly use methods like upsampling and downsampling.
比如我们可以直接通过上采样和下采样的方式
to adjust the overall compression rate for the entire layout.
来调整整个G版面的一个全局的压缩率
This way, the visual memory mechanism supports...
这样视觉记的咳机制就支持
supports higher compression efficiency,
支撑了更高的压缩的效率
and greater compression flexibility.
和更高的压缩的flexibility
In other words, flexibility.
也就是灵活性
So, first, let's take a look at previous memory approaches.
那么我们首先来看一下就是之前的记忆
So, how do text-based memory models approach this problem?
文本记忆的工作是怎么来解决
So, for memory in long contexts... uh...
长上下文中的记忆的呃
Let's take two excellent prior works as examples.
这里以两个非常优秀的之前的工作为例
One is an oral paper published at, uh, XT2026.
一个是发表在呃XT2026的oral的文章
called the 'little sister' agent.
叫妹妹agent
This paper proposes a method.
这篇文章提出了一个方法
So, we have a lot of raw context.
就是我们有很多的原始上下文
So, we take all this raw context and feed it into a text-based agent.
那我们把这些原始上下文给丢给一个文本机
an agent.
智能体
and have the text-based memory agent, uh...
让文本记忆智能体呃
and have it process the raw context section by section, uh...
把原始剩下文一段一段的分别处理呃
After it processes the first segment, it then writes,
他处理完第一段之后去写
forming a memory state for the first paragraph.
形成一个关于第一段的记忆状态
After processing the first... uh...
处理完电呃
Then, it takes the memory state from the first segment to process the second piece of information.
然后拿着第一段的信息状态去处理第二段信息
And it repeats this process iteratively.
然后如此迭代
This process continues until all the original information segments have been processed.
直到所有的原始信息段都被处理完
At this point, the model will take the final memory representation and, uh...
这时候模型会拿着最终的记忆形态去呃
to come up with an answer.
给出一个答案
And uh, there's also some follow-up work.
那呃还有一些后续的工作
For example, the MEL method, uh...
例如麦MEL法呃
So, for these works...
这些工作呢
They utilized, uh, an independent memory agent.
他们利利用就是呃独立的记忆智能体
and a response agent to achieve more flexible, uh, memory interaction.
和回答智能体来实现了更灵活的呃记忆交互
In other words, there's a specialized one that's been specifically trained,
也就是说有一个专门经过训练的
a specialized G-agent,
特殊的G智能体
Its job is to scan the entire memory bank to retrieve information.
负责遍历整个记忆库来提取记忆
And then, a larger, more intelligent large language model,
然后一个更大的更智能的一个log large language model
to then use the information that this intelligent extraction process has gathered,
去对利用这个智能提取到的信息
to answer a question.
对问题做一个回答
So, the paradigm shift we want to propose is this:
那么我们想提出的范式转移
away from the text-based memory forms that current methods use,
就是从刚现在工作的一些文本记忆形态
and shift it to the visual domain that we've proposed.
转移到我们所提出的视觉的domain里面
into the visual domain.
就是vision domin里面
So, under our paradigm,
那我们的在我们的范式下
First, the model browses the retrieved articles within a text-based environment.
模型首先在文本桌面下去浏览检索到的文文章
and browses through some contextual windows.
浏览一些上下文的窗口
and then summarizes the information into, uh, a para-textual form.
然后把信息以副文本形式总结成呃
the paratextual memory
副文本的记忆
And then, when it's time to actually retrieve that memory,
然后在真正调用记忆的时候
Our paratextual memory will then go through a, uh, rendering process.
我们副文本的记忆会经过一个呃rendering
This process renders it into an image, which then becomes the visual memory.
就是经过一个图像的渲染变成视觉的记忆
and then it's used by the model in a visual preview.
然后在视觉预下被模型使用
to be consumed by the model.
被模型consume
So, at this point,
那在这时候呢
So, we'll train the model using different resolutions.
我们就会训练模型以不同的分辨率
and utilize this collection in different, uh, response formats.
以不同的呃回答的形式来去利用这个集
to train the model.
来训练模型
and its ability to utilize memory in a visual context.
在呃视觉一下对记忆的利用能力
And then, the overall answer accuracy rate...
然后整体的一个回答正确率
This is done through a hierarchical reverse computation,
会通过分层的revert计算之后
and joint optimization, uh...
联合的优化额
The overall process includes both the visual and...
整体的包括视觉与
as well as the memory update and memory utilization processes that follow.
包括文本与下面的记忆更新和记忆利用
First, we have the text pre-training for memory drifting.
首先就是呃文本预下memory drifting
During this stage, the model will, uh, continuously observe...
在这个阶段模型会呃不断的观察
that is, the original memory fragments.
就是原始的记忆片段
and uses these original memory fragments to iterate repeatedly, uh...
并且利用原始的记忆片段反复的迭代呃
to repeatedly update its, uh, paratextual memory state.
反复的去更新自己的一个呃副文本的记忆状态
Then, once all the original memory fragments
然后当所有的原始的记忆片段
have all been utilized,
都被利用完了之后
We believe that at this point, the paraphrased text memory state...
我们认为这时候的副文本记忆状态
has reached a converged state.
已经达到了一个收敛的状态
So, we feed it into the RENDERER.
我们就把它送入RENDERER
In other words, our renderer compresses it into a visual memory.
也就是我们的渲染器压缩成visual memory
So, under VISM, the model reads this visual-form memory, uh...
那在VISM面下模型去读这个视觉形态的记忆呃
You can think of it as what happens when a Markdown document is rendered into a PDF.
我们可以理解为一种markdown文档渲染成PDF之后
or an HTML document being rendered into a front-end webpage.
或者是HML文档渲染成前端的网页
So now, it's something that has a layout.
这时候就是一个带有布局的
And the key thing is, it's got...
带有呃关键的就是带有呃
our approach to different pieces of information,
我们对于不同信息的一个
information with different priorities, some emphasized and others de-emphasized.
优先级的强调和不强调的这样一个信息
And then, after the model reads this part of the memory,
然后模型去读这部分的记忆之后
We'll do this through some data augmentation techniques.
我们会通过一些数据增强的方式
to construct different question-answer pairs.
构造不同的q a pairs
to train the model's ability to utilize information with varying levels of importance.
来训练模型对不同力度信息的使用能力
Uh,
呃
So, how do we go about constructing these Q&A pairs?
那么我们怎么去构造这样的QAPS呢
We can think about this from two dimensions.
我们可以以两个维度来思考这个问题
First, we want to train our model.
首先就是我们想要训练模型
and what kind of problem-solving capabilities it should have.
拥有怎样的问题处理能力
So, this is a very empirical question.
那么这里很empirically
So, we can then construct two, uh...
我们就可以去构造两个咳为呃
two, uh, two different types of problem structures.
两个呃两种的问题的结构
One type is crucial.
一种是crucial
and the other is for high-level answers.
关于crucial answer的问答
So, we ask the model this question,
就是我们问模型这个问题
So, for instance, we might ask it for some very high-level answers.
它就是比如说我们问一些很high level的answer
we ask it,
我们问他
We want it to give us a summary answer.
我们希望他去回答出来一个总结性的答案
Then there's another, uh, category.
那另一个呃种类
So, we ask it about some very subtle or low-key information.
就是我们问他一些很低调的信息
So, we ask it some, uh...
就是我们问一些呃
For example, we might ask about some very specific details,
具体它某个比如我们问一些这个很细节
like, what specific words appeared in a particular sentence.
就是具体某一句里面出现了什么样的词语
This allows it to read the image directly.
这样让他直接去读这个图片
So, for these kinds of detailed Q&A tasks,
这样一些detail的问答
So, uh, besides these two classifications at the evidence level,
那额除了这个evidence level的两个分类之外
We can also look at it from the perspective of the memory budget.
我们还可以从memory budget
This corresponds to the classification along the horizontal axis of the image.
也就是图像这里的横轴来去对的分类
So, uh, by giving the model different memory budgets,
那呃给模型不同的memory budget
This means the clarity of the image it can perceive is different.
也就意味着它能看到图像的清晰度是不一样的
It can represent this image using 512 image tokens.
它能用512个图像token来表示这张图片
or it could be represented with as few as 32 tokens.
还是用仅有32个token来表示这张图片
So, under this classification scheme,
那在这个分类维度下
So, we can break down the QA, uh, hierarchy into...
我们可以把QA的呃层级分为
One is reading the high-definition, original information.
一个是有高清原始的信息的读取
In other words, we take the, uh, visual memory...
也就是说我们把呃visual memory
and placing the visual memory into a very high...
visual memory放到一个很高
a state where we use a large number of tokens from the budget to store information.
budget的很多token来存放的一个状态
The other approach is to use a very low memory budget.
另一种就是我们用一个很D的memory button
to store this visual information.
来存放这部分的视觉视觉信息
We compress it down to, uh...
我们把它压缩到呃
For example,
For example
to 32 or 64 tokens.
32个token或者64个token
So, by breaking it down along these two dimensions,
那通过这两个维度的拆解
we can then construct three types of data augmentation patterns.
我们就可以构造三类的数据增强模式
The first one is the most primitive.
一种是最原始的
We don't perform any explicit data augmentation.
我们并不去做明显的数据增强
We just give it the question and the answer directly for a Q&A task.
我们直接把呃问题和答案放给他去做问答
In other words, we're giving it a visual memory without any compression.
也就是我们直接给一个不经压缩的视觉记忆
and a question that's more geared towards, uh, global cognition.
和一个呃更偏向于全局认知的一个呃问题
So, for the other two approaches, we compress the memory separately.
那另外两种形式就是我们分别去压缩记忆
We use a lower me- uh,
我们呃使用更低的me呃
memory budget to represent this memory.
memory budget来表示这个记忆
And then, we still ask it a global question.
然后依依旧问他一个全局的问题
so we expect it to be able to read from the more salient regions of the image,
我们就预期他能从图像当中的一些更显显著的
and from some, uh, emphasized regions, read the knowledge we need.
一些呃被强调的区域读到我们需要的知识
So, another form of data channel...
那另一个额数据的通道形式
So, what we do is we use some, uh, more detailed questions.
就是我们使用一些呃更detail的question
In other words, we're asking about very specific, tiny details or text on the image.
也就是我们去问图像上一些很细节的很小的字
But in this case, we're not going to compress the image.
但是这时候我们不去压缩图片了
we expect the model to be able to read everything completely.
我们就预期模型能够完整地读取
all the information on the entire image.
整张图片上的所有信息
So, by jointly training on these three tasks,
那通过这三种任务的联合训练
This includes the standard Q&A task we just mentioned, where no compression is applied.
包括刚刚提到的standard q a不去做任何压缩
and QA with augmented memory.
以及q a with augmented memory
We compressed its memory state.
我们去把他的记忆状态做了压缩
So, in our actual training, uh...
也就是我们呃在实际训练中
We used a compression ratio of 16x, uh...
使用了16倍的压缩率呃
and we also compress the questions that the model sees.
以及我们对模型所见到的问题做一个压缩
So, we perform, uh, data augmentation.
那做一个呃数据增强
And this gives us three different types of tasks.
我们就可以得到三类不同的任务
So, for these three different types of tasks,
然后我们这三类不同的任务呢
Each of them computes its own loss.
它们分别去计算loss
and optimize both the memory drifting and memory reading stages simultaneously.
同时优化整个呃memory drifting和memory reading两个阶段呃
So, after this, uh, joint training,
那在呃这样的联合训练之后
We tested our model on both single-hop and multi-hop long-context tasks.
我们在呃单跳和和多跳的长城任务上
tested our model.
测试了我们的模型
as well as some previous text-based memory methods.
以及之前的一些基于文本的记忆方法
Uh, so here, uh, the different numbers on the horizontal axis of this table...
呃这里我们呃这个表格横轴的不同的额数字
This represents the number of characters, or tokens, that the model sees during the question-answering process.
它表示了我们在呃QA的过程中
uh, how many characters they'll see in total.
会总共看到多少的字符呃
or rather, how many tokens it will see.
会看到多少的token
So, what we did here was set it to 10K.
也就是这里我们做了10K3
10K, and 100K—these three different settings.
10K和100K这三种设定
And on the vertical axis, these different colors...
那纵轴的这些不同的颜色
represents the number of tokens we give the model to store its memory state.
就代表了我们给模型用于储存他的记忆状态
how many tokens we gave it.
给了他多少个token
to represent this memory during the final answering process.
来在最终的回答过程中表示这个记忆
So, after the memory has been updated,
也就是我们在记忆更新完了之后
it will use a limited memory budget.
会以有限的memory butted
and feed this final memory representation into the model's context.
把最终形态的记忆放到模型的context里面
for question-answering.
用于问答
So, the first thing we can observe is that...
那我们首先可以观察到
Among all the memory-based agents, MAMOOCR
MAMOOCR在所有的记忆智能体中
demonstrates the best overall performance.
展现出了最好的整体性能
Secondly, we can see that...
其次呢我们会发现
As we gradually shrink our memory budget,
随着我们逐渐缩小我们的记忆预算
We want it to, in the downstream process,
我们希望它在下游的过程中
to occupy fewer memory tokens.
占用更少的memory tokens
So, as we can see,
那么我们可以看到
MacOS R can do it with just 16 tokens.
Mac os r可以仅用16个g token
retaining over 80% of the performance compared to using the complete text and image data.
就展现出完整图文下80%以上的保留
retaining over 80% of its full-context capabilities.
与完整头宽下80%以上的能力
However, for some text-based agents,
但是一些文本的智能体
For example, uh, some of the previous text-based baselines...
比如说呃之前的一些基于文本的BASSLINE
So, when these text-based methods are faced with extreme budget constraints,
那这些文本的方法在面临极端即预算的情况下
Their, uh, performance...
他们的呃performance
on average,
一个average
performance...
Performance
you'll see a performance drop of 50% to 60%.
就会出现50%到60%的掉点
Furthermore, we can see that...
此外呢我们可以看到额
So, in the method we proposed,
就是我们所提出的方法中
Layout efficiency.
Layout efficiency
In other words, the real improvement comes from our layout.
也就是我们布局所带来的真正的提升
is greater than the compression we just saw from visual memory.
是大于我们刚看到就是视觉记忆带来的压缩的
So, to prove this point, we designed an oracle analysis.
这里我们设计了一个oracle analysis
to prove this point, uh...
来证明这个观点呃
First, we take the ground truth,
首先我们把ground truth
In other words, we directly feed the actual correct answer into the memory.
也就是真正的正确答案直接放到记忆里面
So, as we were doing this,
呃我们在放的过程中呢
We tried two different setups for this.
放尝试了两种不同的设定
One approach is to place it in the crucial part.
一种是我们把它放到crucial part
In other words, the parts that are, uh, more visually prominent.
也就是呃更显视觉上更显著的那些部分
for example, some higher-level headings.
比如说更high level的一些headings
And for the other type, we place it into some detailed areas.
另一种呢我们就把它放到一些detail的area
So, uh, for example, we use the lowest-level...
就是呃比如说用最低级的一些
um, the lowest-level ones.
就是呃最低level的一些
areas that are purely text-based representations.
就是纯文本表示的一些区域
So, under this oracle injection setup,
那我们在这样的一个oracle injection的设定下
and ran our experiments.
去做实验
And what we find is, uh...
我们会发现呃
When we inject the oracle information into a higher level,
当我们把oracle信息注入到更high level
to more crucial regions,
更crucial的一些区域的话
the model's performance can see a more significant boost.
模型的performance可以带来更明显的提升呃
This is particularly evident in low-memory budget scenarios.
具体体现在尤其是在low memory bug情况下
that is, in the case of 16 memory slots.
也就是16memory body的情况下
The improvement is really significant.
它的提升是非常明显的
as well as multi-hop,
并且在包括multi hop
including single-hop,
包括single hop
and in-distribution tasks.
包括in distribution
aka, HotpotQA.
也就是hop q a
and out-of-distribution scenarios.
包括out of distribution
Uh, that is, in the different cases of 2WikiQAC and NQ...
也就是two weekk和NQ不同的情况下呃
So, for oracle injection into such crucial parts,
这样的crucial part的oracle injection
the performance boost is the most significant.
带来的提升都是最大的
and the most significant.
也是最明显的
But if you do oracle injection in the detail regions,
但是如果在detail的区域做oracle injection
the resulting improvement is relatively moderate.
那么带来的提升是相对来说比较moderated的
And in some, uh, highly compressed scenarios,
并且在一些像呃高压缩度的场景下
Or, let's say, in monotonous scenarios.
或者说在单调的场景下
it can actually lead to a decline in performance.
反而会带来性能下降
After analyzing the results, we found that
我们分析了之后发现
This performance drop is mainly caused by, uh...
这样的性能下降主要来自于呃
the oracle injection for some inefficient regions,
对于一些低效区域的oracle injection
This, in turn, further reduces its readability.
从而使得它的可读性进一步下降
um, which did lower the experimental performance to some extent.
额降低了一部分的实验性能哦
We also have some further analysis.
我们还有一些分析
So, uh, we also wanted to answer...
就是说呃我们还想回答
So, for our, uh, multi-layer...
就是说我们的这样的呃多层
And whether algorithm A can lead the model to allocate resources more effectively,
而A算法是否可以带来模型去更有效的分配
the behavior of allocating a memory budget.
记预算的一个行为呢
We attempted to analyze the model at different training steps.
我们尝试去分析了在不同训练step上面的模型
in its ability to allocate resources between crucial memory and detail memory.
对于crucial memory和detail memory的分配能力
We found that, uh, as the training progresses,
我们发现呃随着训练进行
the model
模型
allocates more to the crucial memory region.
在crucial memory区域去分配
the key information relevant to the correct answer
跟正确答案有关的关键信息
the proportion of key evidence, uh, the behavior of placing key evidence, increases significantly.
关键证据的呃行为的比例明显上升
So, uh, correspondingly, in the less prominent regions...
那么呃相应的在低调的区域
the proportion of information it allocates to these areas shows a significant decrease.
它分配这些信息的比例明显的存在下降呃
Right.
对
And we believe this evidence proves that...
然后我们觉得这样的证据可以证明
As the model progresses through training,
模型随着训练的进行
gradually learned to store information in key regions,
逐渐学到了往关键的区域
to store memories in visually more salient regions.
往视觉上更显著的区域去存放记忆
as well as some of the case studies we've designed.
以及我们设计的一些case study
to showcase the model.
来展示模型
So, what does the final memory storage strategy it learned actually look like?
最终学到的一个记忆储存额策略是什么样子的
So, we can see that the region on the far left is, uh...
我们看到最左边一个区域就是呃
This is a demonstration of the mechanical process of text-based memory.
文本记忆的机械展示了
Let's say...
说
So, if we were to use memory compression on plain text memory,
我们如果在文本的纯文本记忆中使用记忆压缩
For example, memory truncation... uh...
例如记忆截断呃
A simple truncation can cause some evidence...
一个简单的TRACATION会导致额一些证据
key evidence is simply lost.
关键证据直接被丢失
So, what if we base it on visual memory?
那么如果基于视觉记忆呢
With visual memory,
在视觉记忆下
If we don't do any, uh, category or region separation,
如果我们不去做任何的呃分区区分
or, to put it another way, that layout control we just mentioned.
或者说我们刚刚提到的那种布局控制
So, what we'll find is that all the information gets compressed into
那么我们会发现所有的信息都被压缩到了
the smaller characters
比较小的字符
Under high compression rates,
在高压缩率下
These smaller characters are extremely difficult to make out.
这些比较小的字符是很难以辨认的
and the model just can't interpret it.
它是无法被呃模型解读的
So, what if we introduce a mechanism for partitioning memory?
那如果我们引入了记忆分区的机制
In other words, the layout control model.
也就是layout control模型
After undergoing reinforcement learning,
可以在经过强化学习之后
the model can actively learn to
主动学习到
to store key information in higher-level headings,
把一些关键的信息储存到更high level的标题
or, in other words, more visually salient regions.
或者说视觉上更显著的区域
and then store some supporting facts
然后把一些supporting facts
while storing more detailed descriptions in less visually prominent areas.
一些detail的介绍储存到视觉上更不显著的区域
and thereby achieve higher performance with even greater compression rates.
从而实现对于更高压缩率的更高
the survival of the evidence that needs to be fixed, uh...
要修理下的证据存活额
We also conducted a statistical test on our main timeline table.
我们还对我们的主时间表格做了统计学检验
Finally, we found that, uh...
最后我们发现呃
all the evidence in the main results tables.
所有的主时间表格中的证据
that is, the ones in the main timeline table, uh...
就是主时间表格中的呃
The experimental results include, uh...
实验结果包括呃
the improvements on each dataset and the average improvement.
每个数据集上和average上面的提升
and all of these results are statistically robust.
都是比较统计学上鲁棒的
Additionally, we conducted a more complex analysis.
此外我们进行了复杂的分析
We found that, uh, MOSR brings a visual improvement.
我们发现呃麦MOSR带来的一个视觉提升
And the computational overhead that comes with it is, uh, relatively acceptable.
它伴随的额计算开销是相对来说可接受的
So, we can see here, uh...
我们可以看这里的呃
Each of these numbers represents the time it takes for us to process, uh, a single sample.
每个数字都代表了我们呃处理每一个sample
In other words, how many seconds it takes to process each sample.
也就是每一个样本需要多少秒
We'll find that, uh, it's kind of cute, acting all cute.
我们会发现呃卖萌卖萌
the speed at which CR processes information.
CR处理的信处理信息的速度
In some, uh, shorter contextual processes,
在一些比较呃短的上下文过程中
This does introduce some additional overhead.
它是会带来额外的overhead的
a pretty significant overhead.
比较明显的外o pa
But as the context gets longer,
但是随着上下文变长
its overhead actually decreases.
它的overhead反而会降低
And what we found was, uh...
我们发现这是呃
This is because, during the overall compression process,
因为就是它在整体压缩过程中
Its overall compression rate is higher than some other text-based methods.
它的额整体压缩率是比一些其他的文本
baseline methods.
BASSLINE要更
is much higher.
就是要更高的
It can do so with fewer tokens.
它可以更少的token
So, as we were just saying,
也就是我们刚刚所提到的
So, for 512 tokens to represent the same amount of, uh...
就是512个token表示同样的呃
I mean, the amount of information.
就是信息信息量
This, in turn, shortens its inference time.
从而使得他的推理时间变得更短
We also compared some larger base models that hadn't been through the R1 process.
我们还去比较了一些未经过R1的更大的基模
to demonstrate the effectiveness of our R1.
来体现我们R1的作用
Here, we compared the ones without...
我们这里比较了没有
the Qwen-VL 7B model after RL and, uh...
经过RL的千万VL7B和呃
the 32B and 72B models, uh...
32B和72B呃
So, these are some of the baselines for Qwen 2.5 VL, uh...
这些都是千万2.5VL的一些基线呃
Uh, compared to the Qwen 2.5 VL 7B model that was fine-tuned with RL,
呃相比于经过R1的请问2.5BL7B模型
or in other words, all the larger-scale models of MAMOCL.
也就是MAMOCL所有的更大的规模的模型
all showed a certain degree of decline in their average performance.
都显展现出了一定程度的平均水平下降
And, uh, in multi-hop scenarios,
并且在呃多跳环境下
In other words, for more complex problems.
也就是一些更复杂的问题
um, that are revealed during the solving process...
解决过程中展现出的呃
the performance gap becomes even more pronounced.
performance DP会更加的明显
And we also analyzed some failure cases.
并且我们还分析了一些failure case
In other words, under what circumstances...
也就是什么样的情况下
our strategy would face challenges.
卖包子牙的额策略会遇到挑战
In other words, what kind of questions does our strategy...
也就是说我们的策略在什么样的问题
and what kind of queries might pose some risks.
什么样的query下面会存在一些风险
We've primarily identified two, uh, rather significant failure modes.
我们主要发现了两类呃比较显著的failure mode
The first failure mode is, uh...
第一个failure mode就是呃
we lose some fine-grained details during our memory compression process.
我们的记忆压缩过程中丢失了一些fine green details
For instance, let's say we want to ask, uh...
比如说我们想问说呃
between these two people, uh, which one's level is more professional?
这两个人哪个人的呃水平更professional
So, when the model is compressing the information,
那么模型在压缩的时候
it would go and investigate each of these two individuals.
他分别去调查了这两个人
But when it came to storing the key information,
但是他在储存关键信息的时候
It didn't put the part that actually contributes to the answer,
他并没有把直接贡献答案的那部分
He placed the key information in a more prominent position.
关键信息放到一个更醒目的位置
He just took the, uh, titles of these two people
他只是把这两个人的呃标题
In other words, it doesn't really provide any information gain.
也就是并不产生什么信息增益的
This information was placed at a higher heading level.
这些信息放到了更高的一个headings level
So, for the memory compressed in this way,
那么这样压缩出来的记忆
uh, it doesn't really make a positive contribution to the final answer.
就并不能有对final answer的一个正向的贡献呃
So, for Fillet Mode B, which is during the visual compression process,
fillet mode b也就是在视觉压缩过程中
the model has written down too much information.
模型撰写了过多的信息
Its information density is fixed.
它的信息密度一定的
Meanwhile,
同时
too much information will lead to, uh...
过多的信息就会导致呃
the readability of certain parts of the overall visual memory drops sharply.
整体的视觉记忆中的部分信息可读性急剧下降
leading to it being incorrectly identified during the reasoning process, uh...
导致在推理过程中无法被正确辨认呃
For example, here, when the question is, uh...
例如在这里当问题是呃
when a past event occurred, the model, uh...
过去一个事件什么时候发生模型呃
So, the actual correct answer is...
那么真正的正确答案就是
at some point in the past, uh...
它在过去的某个时间点呃
And the answer is February 14th, 2015.
这里的答案就是2015年的2月14日
But as the model was answering,
但是模型在回答过程中
It kept emphasizing certain pieces of information over and over again.
他把一些呃信息反复强调了很多次
This causes the total amount of information...
导致整体的一个信息总量
exceeds its capacity.
超出了一个能够承载的范围
This ultimately affects the quality of the compression.
导致最终压缩出来的效果
and it can't identify the correct information.
无法辨认正确正确信息
leading to incorrect answers.
导致回答错误
Uh...
额
So, that's all for my part.
以上就是我这部分
and that's our technical explanation for this part.
我们这部分呃技术的一个讲解
So, are there any questions?
请问有什么问题吗
Alright, thank you, Yaorui. Uh...
好的谢谢耀瑞呃
Could you share your PPT again? Right.
您的PPT可以重新共享着对
Otherwise, the livestream might start acting up later.
要不待会直播间可能会异常行
So, besides everyone who's here in the livestream today,
那除了今天直播间的小伙伴们
We also have some of our own colleagues from the company listening in.
我们公司内部的同学也有在听
And with that, I have two questions for everyone.
然后内部有两个问题跟大家问一下
Alright, so the first one, uh...
首先第一个呃
When compressing the interaction history into a visual layout for memory,
把交互历史压缩成视觉布局来记忆时
So, how is the information density distributed across different regions?
不同区域的信息密度是怎么分配的
So, is there any type of information that's particularly prone to being lost during this compression process?
有没有哪类信息在压缩过程中特别容易丢失
Right, so for our allocation strategy in this part...
嗯嗯呃我们对于这部分的分配策略
we tend to use reinforcement learning.
倾向于使用强化学习
to let the model manage it autonomously.
让模型自主管理
allocation strategy.
分配策略
We don't manually, uh...
我们不会手动的去呃
to assign it some allocation strategies that it must follow.
给它assign1些必须要follow的分配策略
So, as the reinforcement learning converges,
那随着强化学习的收敛
We found that the model tends to place certain information that is more crucial to the answer...
我们发现模型更倾向于把一些对于答案
and placing the information that contributes more to the correctness of the final answer into, uh...
final answer的正确性贡献更大的信息放到呃
the crucial area,
Crucial area
and place some of the less-contributing supporting facts into, uh...
把一些贡献不那么大的一些supporting facts给放到呃
into the more secondary areas, uh...
比较次要的区域呃
So, what about which parts are more likely to be lost?
那关于哪些部分更容易丢失
In the failure mode analysis we just did, uh...
我们在刚刚的呃fire mode analysis里面
We found that for certain types of questions, like those involving comparison,
发现在一些类似于涉及到对比的问题
For instance, when it's asked questions like, "Which is better, A or B?"... uh...
比如说a or b哪个更好这些问题的时候呃
due to some of its internal capabilities,
模型由于一些内部能力
For instance, differences in its initial capabilities.
比如初始能力的差异
It tends to, uh...
他倾向于会把额
that is, it puts both A and B into a relatively less important area.
就是A和B都放到比较枯燥的区域
But it will, uh, overlook some things.
但是会呃忽略一些
regarding some of the information that comes up during the comparison process,
就关于比较的过程中产生的一些
for instance, the relative relationship between A and B.
比如A跟B之间的相对关系
It will incorrectly place these parts into the auxiliary information area.
他会把这些部分错误的给放到auxiliary
the region for information.
information的区域
We believe this might be, uh, an issue with the model...
我们认为这个可能是一个呃模型
an ability of the starting point.
starting point的一个能力
Perhaps this could be achieved by making changes to the COSTART, or, uh, during the pre-training stage.
可能能通过COSTART或者是呃预训练阶段的改变
to solve these issues.
来解决这些事情
Okay, thanks.
嗯好的谢谢
The second question is, compared to serializing the history...
第二个问题是相比把历史序列化
a solution that serializes it into plain text,
序列化成纯文本的方案
using a visual layout for memory.
用视觉布局做记忆
In which reasoning scenarios is this advantage most pronounced?
在哪些推理场景下优势最明显
When the contextual budget is extremely tight,
上下文预算极端紧张时
So, what are its limitations?
效果的边界在哪
We'll find that this kind of visualized memory...
我们会发现这样视觉化的记忆
One of its very clear advantages is that...
的一个很明显的优势
So, uh, in certain multimodal interaction scenarios,
就是呃它在一些多模态的交互场景下
For example, let's say we actually need to store something in the, uh, memory bank.
比如说我们真的需要往呃记忆库中存放
mixed information of images and text,
图片和文本的混合信息
or when dealing with mixed information that includes things like video and audio.
或者在包括视频音频这些混合信息的时候
So, multimodal memory itself, compared to unimodal memory that's purely text-based,
多模态的记忆本身相比于纯文本的单模态记忆
has a natural advantage.
会有天然的优势
So, regarding the boundaries of the information itself...
呃那么关于呃信息本身的边界
I think this is, uh...
我觉得这个是一个呃
a problem that is quite reliant on the base model's own capabilities.
比较依赖基模本身能力的问题
Uh, and as we all know,
呃我们也都知道
Like, uh, for visual models such as ViT,
像呃像with transformer这样的一些视觉的
or, let's say, within multimodal transformers,
或者说多模态的transformer里面
it inherently has some... for visual information,
它本身对于视觉信息是会有一些
compression algorithms based on convolution.
基于卷积的压缩算法的
So, uh, some of the current methods...
那么呃呃现在的一些方法
This ensures that after I perform the sampling,
它可以保证说我当下采样当三破零之后
So, after sampling many times,
当sampling很多次之后
the features we obtain can still be processed by our Transformer.
我们的得到的feature依然可以被我们transformer
and ultimately identify it for us.
最终辨识出我们
So, I think the key issue here regarding the readability of this visual information...
那我觉得这里关于视觉信息的可读性
a key bottleneck lies in, uh...
的一个关键瓶颈在于呃
the text recognition ability of the Vision Transformer, or the base model, uh...
wet transformer或者说基模的呃文本辨识能力
or, to put it another way, how much the base model can handle.
或者说他对于基模能对于多少下
the images, even at high sampling rates, still remain recognizable.
采样倍率的图片依然保持辨识度
Uh, as long as the base model's capabilities can support it,
呃只要基膜的能力能支持住
So, uh, the model itself, based on this compressed information...
那么呃模型本身基于这些被压缩的信息
and then perform inference.
再去进行推理
It's an ability that can be, uh, that can be trained.
就是一个可以被呃可以被训练
an ability that can be cultivated.
可以被培养的一个能力